World Federation of Trade Unions Records 5595
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Executive Bureau meeting - Item 1 of the agenda - Strengthening of worker's united action and the development of actions for the defense of their economic and social interests - Rapporteur: Louis Saillant, 1951-07-02-1951-07-06 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  49 page mimeographed typescript
- Executive Bureau meeting - Item 2 of the agenda - Opposing America's remilitarization of Japan - Reporter: Liu Ning, 1951-07-02-1951-07-06 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Executive Bureau meeting - Item 3 of the agenda - Report on the activity of the Textile Worker's Trade Department - Reporter - A. Burski, 1951-07-02-1951-07-06 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  17 page mimeographed typescript
- Executive Bureau meeting - Item 3 of the agenda - Report on the activity of the Miners' Trade Department - Rapporteur: H. Turrel, 1951-07-02-1951-07-06 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Executive Bureau meeting - Item 4 of the agenda - Information on Social Security, 1951-07-02-1951-07-06 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Executive Bureau meeting - Information on the WFTU delegation to Israel, 1951-07-02-1951-07-06 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- General Council meeting - General Report of Activity, Volume I, 1951-11-15-1951-11-21 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  74 page mimeographed typescript
- General Council meeting - General Report of Activity, Volume II, 1951-11-15-1951-11-21 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- General council meeting - Official texts published since the 2nd WTU Congress Milan, July 1949, 1951-11-15-1951-11-21 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  231 page mimeographed typescript
- WFTU General Council - Point 3 - General report of activity of the WFTU - Rapporteur Louis Saillant, General Secretary, WFTU, 1951-11-15-1951-11-21 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- General council Speech by Comrade W.W. Kaznetsov on point 4 of the agenda, 1951-11-15-1951-11-21 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- WFTU General Council - Point 4 - Workers unity in the struggle to raise living standards and against the economic and social consequences of the policy of war preparations - Rapporteur: Benoit Frachon, 1951-11-15-1951-11-21 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Executive Bureau meeting - Point I - The present struggles of the workers and the defense of trade union rights - Rapporteur: Louis Saillant, 1952-06-09-1952-06-15 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  97 page mimeographed typescript
- Third World Trade Union Congress - Item I - Report of activity of the WFTU and the tasks arising for the trade unions in strengthening united action of the workers in the fight for the improvement of their living standards and in defense of peace- Rapporteur: Louis Saillant, 1953-10-10-1953-10-21 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  70 page mimeographed typescript
- Third World Trade Union Congress - Point II of the agenda - Report of Brother Giuseppe Di Vittorio, President of the WFTU - Tasks for the trade unions for economic and social development and in the struggle for national independence and democratic liberties in the capitalist and colonial countries - Reporter: G. Di Vittorio, 1953-10-10-1953-10-21 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  42 page mimeographed typescript
- Third World Trade Union Congress - Item III - Development of the trade union movement in the colonial and semi-colonial countries - Reporter: Ruslan Widjajasastra, General Secretary, Central Bureau of all Indonesian Trade Centre, 1953-10-10-1953-10-21 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Speech - Saillant: Speech by brother Louis Saillant in concluding the discussion on the first item on the agenda of the 3rd World Trade Union Congress, 1953-10-14 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Speeches - Le Leap, Shvernik, Santi: Speech of Brother Alain Le Leap, General Secretary of the French, CGT, 1953-10-12 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Speeches - Le Leap, Shvernik, Santi: Speech by N.M. Shvernik, President of the All Union Council of Trade Unions at the 3rd World Trade Union Congress, 1953-10-11 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Speech by Fernando Santi, Secretary of the Italian General Confederation of Labor, 1953-10-13 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Bulletins of the 3rd World Trade Union Congress (WTUC): Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Saturday, 1953-10-10 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Bulletins of the 3rd World Trade Union Congress (WTUC): Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Sunday, 1953-10-11 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Bulletins of the 3rd World Trade Union Congress (WTUC): Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Monday, 1953-10-12 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Bulletins of the 3rd World Trade Union Congress (WTUC): Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Tuesday, 1953-10-13 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Bulletins of the 3rd World Trade Union Congress (WTUC): Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Wednesday, 1953-10-14 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Bulletins of the 3rd World Trade Union Congress (WTUC): Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Thursday, 1953-10-15 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Bulletins of the 3rd WTUC: Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Friday, 1953-10-16 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Bulletins of the 3rd WTUC: Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Saturday, 1953-10-17 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Bulletins of the 3rd WTUC: Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Sunday, 1953-10-18 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  815 page mimeographed typescript
- Bulletins of the 3rd WTUC: Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Monday, 1953-10-19 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Bulletins of the 3rd WTUC: Bulletin of the 3rd WTUC, Summary of Tuesday, 1953-10-20 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- World Conference of Agricultural and Forestry Workers: World Conference of Agricultural and Forestry Workers - 1st item on the agenda - The conditions of the Agricultural and Forestry Workers and their fight for their economic and social demands. Report by the Secretary Ilo Bosi, 1953-10-24-1953-10-28 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  38 page mimeographed typescript
- World Conference of Agricultural and Forestry Workers: World Conference of Agricultural and Forestry Workers - 2nd item on the agenda - Strengthening of help to peasants in the fight for their basic instincts - Report by R. Vidimari, 1953-10-24-1953-10-27 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- 7th Session of the General Council - 1st item - The International Situation and the implementation of the decisions of the 3rd World Trade Union Congress on the development of the unity of the workers in the fight for their demands. Rapporteur: Louis Saillant, 1954-12-09-1954-12-14 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  72 page mimeographed typescript
- Summary of Louis Saillant's report to the seventh session of the General Council of the WFTU, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Seventh Session of the General Council - Item 1 on the agenda (Appendix) - The development of the struggles for demands throughout the world, 1954-12-09-1954-12-14 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  87 page mimeographed typescript
- Seventh Session of the General Council - 2nd Item - The charter of Trade Union Rights and the International Campaign to defend and win trade union and democratic rights - Rapporteur: Giuseppe di Vittorio, 1954-12-09-1954-12-14 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Seventh Session of the General Council - Proposed amendments to the definition of the rights to appear in the Charter of Trade Union Rights, 1954-12-09-1954-12-14 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- General resolution of the seventh session of the General Council of the WFTU, 1954-12-09-1954-12-14 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Item II, 2 - Definition of the rights to appear in the Charter of Trade Union Rights, 1954-06-26-1954-06-28 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- (Draft) Charter of Trade Union Rights, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- World Conference of Women Workers (WCWW): WCWW - 1st item - The united struggle of women workers and trade unions for increases wages, for the application of the principle of equal pay for equal work, against all forms of discrimination, for the improvement of their living conditions the winning of their rights and for peace - by Germaine Guille, Secretary of the French General Confederation of Labor (CGI), 1956-06-14-1956-06-17 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- World Conference of Women Workers (WCWW): WCWW - 2nd item - For a more active participation by women in the life and leadership of the trade unions, for large scale trade union recruitment by Tsune Deushi, Head, Women's Department of Teacher's Union of Saitama Prefecture, Japan, 1956-06-14-1956-06-17 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- 8th session of the General Council - Report on the 1st item of the agenda - 'Actions for the present economic and social demands of the workers and the development of new trends for unity of the International trade Union movement,' delivered by Louis Saillant, General Secretary, WFTU, 1956-09-27-1956-10-03 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  65 page mimeographed typescript
- 8th Session of the General council - report on the 2nd item - 'The trade union movement in countries which have just won their independence or are struggling to win it and fraternal solidarity amongst all workers in the struggle against colonialism,' delivered by Abdoulaye Diallo, Vice President, WFTU, 1956-09-27-1956-10-03 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- 8th Session of the General Council - Report on the main activities of the WFTU, 1956-09-27-1956-10-03 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  79 page mimeographed typescript
- 8th Session of the General Council - Report on the convocation of the 4th World Trade Union Congress (4th point of the agenda) - delivered by Giuseppe Casadei, 1956-09-27-1956-10-03 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Report of the Delegation of the WFTU to Hungary, 1956-11-23-1956-11-27 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  77 page mimeographed typescript
- 13th Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the first item on the agenda - The activities of the WFTU and the preparation of the 4th World Trade Union Congress, 1957-01-29-1957-01-31 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  31 page mimeographed typescript
- 13th Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the fifth point of the agenda - The development of united action by the workers to achieve their demands in the mines and factories of the European coal and steel community, 1957-01-29-1957-01-31 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- European trade Union and Workers Conference against the threat of Atomic War and for Peace: Speech by Louis Saillant, General Secretary, World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU), 1958-06-20-1958-06-22 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- European trade Union and Workers Conference against the threat of Atomic War and for Peace: Appeal of the European Trade Union and Workers Conference, 1958-06-20-1958-06-22 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- First World Conference of Young Workers: Report on 1st point - Wages, vocational training; Young workers trade union and social rights, their struggles and those of the trade union for their demands and against discrimination - Speaker Charles Salducci, 1958-07-14-1958-07-20 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- First World Conference of Young Workers: Report on 2nd item - Prospects for Young Workers throughout the world and their united action for peace against danger of an atomic or thermonuclear war - Presented by Hiroshi Yamakawa, 1958-07-14-1958-07-20 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- First World Conference of Young Workers: Report on 3rd item - The role of the trade union in organizing and uniting young workers and the part young people play in the strengthening of the trade union - Speaker Lazaro Pena, Secretary of the WFTU, 1958-07-14-1958-07-20 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- 19th Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the first item on the agenda - Growing tasks of the WFTU in the fight for peace - Speaker: Luigi Grassi, Secretary of the WFTU, 1959-04-02-1959-04-06 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- 19th Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the Development of the Workers Economic and Social Demands - Presented by Marcel Bras, Secretary of the WFTU, 1959-04-02-1959-04-06 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- International Trade Union Committee for Solidarity with the workers and people of Algeria: Report of the Secretariat of the International Trade Union Committee for solidarity with the workers and people of Algeria - Report on the Solidarity campaigns in the various countries, 1962-06-1962-07 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- International Trade Union Committee for Solidarity with the workers and people of Algeria: Speech by the representative of the WFTU, Ibrahin Zakaria, Secretary of the WFTU, 1962-06-28-1962-07-01 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- International consultative Trade Union Conference on the Economic and Social Consequences of the European Economic Community and the policy of the monopolies: Report presented by Brother Louis Saillant, General Secretary of the WFTU, 1962-12-14-1962-12-17 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  94 page mimeographed typescript
- International consultative Trade Union Conference on the Economic and Social Consequences of the European Economic Community and the policy of the monopolies: Concluding speech by Brother Louis Saillant, General Secretary of the WFTU, 1962-12-14-1962-12-17 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- International Trade Union and Legal Commission for the Defense and Extension of Trade Union Rights and the Protection of the Victims of Anti-Trade Union Repression; World Federation of Trade Unions: 2nd Session - Report - Speaker: Edvin Chleboun, Secretary of the World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU), 1963-07-17-1963-07-19 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- International Trade Union and Legal Commission for the Defense and Extension of Trade Union Rights and the Protection of the Victims of Anti-Trade Union Repression; World Federation of Trade Unions: Declaration of the 2nd Session of the International Trade Union and Legal Commission, 1963-07-17-1963-07-19 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- International Trade Union and Legal Commission for the Defense and Extension of Trade Union Rights and the Protection of the Victims of Anti-Trade Union Repression; World Federation of Trade Unions: Press communique - For the defense and extension of trade union rights and for the protection of victims of anti-trade union repression, 1963-07-24 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  2 page mimeographed typescript
- Federation Syndicale Mondiale (FSM): XIIIeme Session du Conseil General - Rapport - Sur la realisation de la politique unitaire de la FSM pour la defense des interest et des droits des Travailleurs, et lexeme des lutes ouvriers dans le monde, en liaison avec l 'application du Programme d'Action adopted par le Veme Congres Syndical Mondial - Rapporteur: Louis Saillant, Secretaire General de la FSM, 1964-10-19-1964-10-24 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 13th Session of the General Council (Various conclusions, resolution, and amendment texts), 1964-10-30 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  39 page mimeographed typescript
- 2nd Plenary Conference of the World Trade Union Committee for Consultation and United Action against Monopolies. Report on a joint trade union policy for the development of international trade and on the program for organization of a world trade union conference on this subject - Speaker: comrade Louis Saillant, General Secretary of the World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU), 1964-12-14-1964-12-17 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  60 page mimeographed typescript
- 2nd Plenary Conference of the World Trade Union Committee for Consultation and United Action against Monopolies - Concluding speech by Brother Louis Saillant, 1964-12-14-1964-12-17 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- 6th World Trade Union Congress (WTUC) Report on the first point of the agenda - Examination of the application o the program of trade union action and steps taken by the WFTU to promote unity, the present evolution and development of the world trade union movement, the new opportunities for unity, solidarity and international trade union relations - Presented by Louis Saillant, General Secretary of the WFTU, 1965-10-08-1965-10-22 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- 6th WTUC - Report on the second item on the agenda - On the development of international trade union solidarity with the struggles of the workers and peoples of the colonial and newly liberated countries for the winning and consolidation of national independence, for independent economic and social development against imperialism, colonialism and neo-colonialism - Presented by Luis Padilla, Secretary of the WFTU, 1965-10-08-1965-10-22 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- 6th WTUC - Report on the third item on the agenda - The situation in Vietnam and the struggle of the Vietnamese workers and people against the American imperialist aggressors: a) For the Trade Union Federation of the Democratic Republic of Vietnam - Speaker: Brother Hoang Quoc Viet, Chairman of the T.U.F.N.V., Member of the Executive Committee of the World Federation of trade Unions (WFTU), 1965-10-08-1965-10-22 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- 6th WTUC - Report on the intensification of the war of aggression waged by the American imperialists in South Vietnam and the legitimate patriotic struggle of the South Vietnamese workers and population - Speaker: Tran Hoai Nam, Member of the Permanent Committee of the Central Committee of the Federation of Trade Unions for the Liberation of South Vietnam, 1965-10-08-1965-10-22 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Federation Syndicale Mondiale: 51eme Session du Bureau Executif-Rapport sur la realisation du plan de travail de la FSM en application des decisions du Vieme Congres Syndicale Mondiale - Presente par le cde. Pierre Gensous, Secretaire General - adjoint de la FSM, 1966-02-28-1966-03-02 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- 32nd Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the 1st item on the agenda - WFTU activity and tasks following the 6th WTUC, with special emphasis on solidarity action in support of workers in struggle for economic and social demands, and in support of the workers and people of Vietnam - Report given by Pierre Gensous, Assistant General Secretary of the WFTU, 1966-05-26-1966-05-28 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- 32nd Session of the Executive Committee - Report on the third item on the agenda - 'The Activities of the TUI's' - Presented by Raul Silvestri, Secretary of the WFTU, 1966-05-26-1966-05-28 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- 16th Session of the General Council - Report on the first item on the agenda - The activity and tasks of the WFTU since the VI Congress especially with regard to the development of unity, action, and international solidarity on behalf of: the workers and people of Vietnam, the workers struggling for their economic and social demands, the workers and peoples struggling for peace and against imperialism, colonialism, and neo- colonialism - Report of Pierre Gensous, Assistant General Secretary of the WFTU, 1966-12-06-1966-12-09 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- 16th Session of the General Council General Resolution; Declarations; Decisions (Drafts), 1966-12-06-1966-12-09 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- World Trade Union Committee for Consultation and United Action against the Monopolies: Report. Joint Trade Union Action for the Development of International Trade and Economic Relations in the Interests of the Workers and Peoples by Louis Saillant, General Secretary of the WFTU, 1966-12-14-1966-12-17 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  101 page mimeographed typescript
- Federation Syndicale Mondiale: 54e session du Bureau Executif de la FSM Rapport sur l'etat des activities de propagande de la FSM et les possibilities d 'amelioration dans ce domain - Rapporteur: V.A. Podzerko, Secretary de la FSM, 1967-04-11-1967-04-13 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- 34th session of the Executive Committee - Report on 'The Development of the WFTU's Work in the United Nations (UNO) and its specialized agencies' - Speaker: Stan Dragoni, Secretary of the WFTU, 1967-10-25-1967-10-27 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- 34th session of the Executive Committee - Report on the work of the WFTU in developing new international trade union relationships and the united action of workers and union organizations all over the world in the cause of the well-being, liberty and independence of people for peace, and against imperialist acts of aggression, particularly in Vietnam and the Middle East - Speaker: Pierre Gensous, Assistant General Secretary WFTU, 1967-10-25-1967-10-27 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- 34th session of the Executive Committee - (Resolutions and Decisions, Numbers 1-18), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  27 page mimeographed typescript
- Federation Syndicale Mondiale: Service de Presse de la FSM, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Documents adopted by the World Trade Unions Conference on vocational training, 1968-02-01-1968-02-04 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- 18th session of the General Council Report on the first item on the agenda - The WFTU's activities in the present situation to develop international trade union unity for the triumph of the economic and social demands of the working class of peace and of national independence, and to put a definite end to American imperialism's aggression in Vietnam - Speaker: Pierre Gensous, Assistant General Secretary of the World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU), 1968-12-16-1968-12-19 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  45 page mimeographed typescript
- 18th session of the General Council Report on the second item on the agenda - The WFTU's work for training trade union officials - Speaker: Edvin Chleboun, Secretary of the WFTU, 1968-12-06-1968-12-09 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- 18th session of the General Council Report on the third item on the agenda - Convocation and preparation of the 7th World Trade Union Congress, 1968-12-06-1968-12-09 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- 18th session of the General Council (Drafts; Resolutions and Decisions, 1968-12-16-1968-12-19 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  50 page mimeographed typescript
- 18th session of the General Council Plan of Work until the 7th World Trade Union Congress - Appendix to the reports presented tot eh Council, 1968-12-16-1968-12-19 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- 35th session of the Executive Committee - 3rd point of the agenda - Report on requests for affiliations - Speaker: Mahendra Sen, Secretary of the WFTU, 1968-12-15 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- 35th session of the Executive Committee - (Resolutions and Decisions Numbers 1-7), 1968-12-15 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Document on trade union policy and action for preparation of the 7th World Trade Union Congress, 1969-06-05 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- 7th World Trade Union Congress (WTUC) - Report on the first point on the agenda - The role, tasks, and responsibilities of the WFTU and trade unions for workers in the struggle for social progress, trade union and democratic liberties, national independence, peace, against monopolistic exploitation, imperialism, colonialism and neo- colonialism - Speaker: Pierre Gensous, World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU) Assistant Secretary General, 1969-10-17-1969-10-26 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  108 page mimeographed typescript
- 7th World Trade Union Congress (WTUC) - 1st report on the second point of the agenda - The situation in Vietnam and the struggle of workers and people of Vietnam against the American imperialist aggressors for the restoration of peace in Vietnam and for the development of solidarity of the workers and the people of the world - Speaker: Hoang Quoc Viet, President of the Federation of Trade Unions of Vietnam, 1969-10-17-1969-10-26 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- 7th WTUC - 2nd report on the second point of the agenda - Speaker: Tran Hoi Nam, Member of the permanent committee of the Trade Union Federation for the liberation of South Vietnam, 1969-10-17-1969-10-26 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- 7th WTUC - Report on the third point of the agenda - The problems of trade unions in developing countries - Speaker: Ibrahim Zakaria, WFTU Secretary, 1969-10-17-1969-10-31 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- 7th WTUC - Report on the 4th point of the agenda - The trade unions and scientific and technical progress, 1969-10-17-1969-10-31 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Constitution of the WFTU, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- 7th World Trade Union Congress: 7th World Trade Union Congress - Speech by Comrade Luciano Lama, Secretary of the General Confederation of Italian Workers (CGI), 1969-10-17-1969-10-26 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- 7th World Trade Union Congress: Speech by President of AUCCTU Comrade A.N. Chelepin at the 7th World Trade Union Congress, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  24 page booklet
- Documents for preparation and discussion of 25th anniversary of London Conference, 1969-12-18 (Box 4, Folder 24)